

Dilan Amarasinghe

Full Stack Software Engineer

☑ dilan.amarasinghe214263@gmail.com 🤳 +94779689515

• 48, Kahanthota Road, 10115 Malabe

Profile

I am a full-stack software engineer with more than 3 years of industrial experience. I am a fast learner who has the passion and self-motivation to learn and explore new things. I could utilize my skills and experiences gained through relevant education and projects and improve technical/non-technical skills by giving the best input to your organization. Working at my maximum effort towards achieving the target in an efficient manner would be my mission.

Education

B. Sc In Information Technology

2017 - 2020

Sri Lanka Institute Of Information Technology, Colombo

Second Upper (WGPA 3.48)

Dean's List: From 2017 to 2018 and 2020

Employment

Software Engineer

Aug 2021 - Present

Rootcode Labs, Colombo

Responsibilities:

- Engaged in an incident reporting admin application, designing the database schema and automation of data migration from excel to the database(Nest JS, React JS, MySQL) - Hashtag Generation
- Engaged in a video conferencing web and admin application(Nest JS, React JS, MySQL) - Expert Republic

Software Engineer

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

Zone24x7 (Pvt) Ltd (Outsourced to Circles.Life), Colombo

Responsibilities:

- Engaged in a telco project which is being currently launched to Singapore, Australia, Japan, etc.. with more than 10000 user base.
- Tools & Technologies NodeJS, Vanila JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Golang, Jenkins
- Roles played Backend, Frontend, Deployment

Personal details

Date of birth October 24th, 1997

Nationality Sri Lankan

Website confident-euler-920d46.netlify.app

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/dilanamarasinghe-45a94b147

Github github.com/dilanSuraj

StackOverflow stackoverflow.com/users/103 48303/dilan-amarasinghe

SoundCloud medium.com/@dilan.amaras inghe214263

Pinterest pinterest.com/dilanamarasin ghe214263

Quora

quora.com/profile/Dilan-Amarasinghe-1

My Blog

surajblog915104510.wordpress .com

Twitter

twitter.com/dilan96297450

SoundCloud

soundcloud.com/dilanamarasinghe

Full Stack Software Engineer

Half Life (Private) Limited, Colombo

Responsibilities:

- Engaged in a project to implement centralized authentication system and designing database schema (PostgresSQL, ReactJS, Nodejs/ExpressJs, DigitalOcean)
- Engaged in a Survey Management web and admin application and designing database schema(PostgresSQL, Nodejs/ExpressJs, React JS/Redux, DigitalOcean)
- Engaged in a project to implement trace web and admin application and designing database schema(PostgresSQL, Nodejs/ExpressJs, React JS/Redux,Digital Ocean)
- Engaged in a project to implement trace mobile application(
 Flutter)
- Engaged in a project to implement data sync command line application(Python, OAuth, Docker)
- Engaged in a project to implement google analytics (Python, OAuth, Google Analytics)
- Manasa Project (PostgresSQL, ReactJS, Nodejs/ExpressJs, Digital Ocean)
- Worked under an Agile Environment.
- Deployment and maintaing of the projects.
- Roles played Backend, Frontend, Deployment

Undergraduate Trainee

Nov 2018 - Oct 2019

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

IFS Research & Development (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo

Responsibilities:

- Engaged in a project to convert a desktop application to a web and mobile application.
- Engaged in a project to convert MS Installer to WIX Installer.
- Worked with Oracle PL/SQL.
- Worked under an Agile Environment.
- Worked with JIRA.

Certificates

AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud-Native

Aug 2020

- Coursera

https://coursera.org/share/1761264dd5b0becc2f7e3beeeaa66823

Getting Started with Google Kubernetes

Oct 2020

Engine - Coursera

https://coursera.org/share/bcd7d1b87638e620bb054f7006235483

Skills

Nest JS

Node JS

Express JS

React JS

TypeORM

Jitsi

Java

Javascript

MySQL

NoSQL

Oracle PL/SQL

PostgressSQL

GoLang

Python

AWS

MongoDB

Spring Framework

SonarQube

Jenkins

VueJS

Nuxt JS

AWS Serverless

Firebase Serverless

Machine Learning

Flask Rest API

HTML

scss/css

TypeScript

GraphQL

Linux

OOP

REST

Introduction to Domain Names and Web Sep 2020 Hosting - Quick Guide - Udemy https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-5f348e66-296f-40ed-9b3d-de6e247345c4/

The Complete SQL Course 2020: Become Sep 2020 a MYSQL Master - Udemy https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-07381592-aa69-4446-

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-07381592-aa69-4446-9821-999dac48a1ae/

Building Serverless Apps on AWS -

Oct 2020

LinkedIn

http://www.linkedin.com/learning/building-serverless-apps-on-aws-2?trk=flagship-

lil_details_certification&trk=lil_details_certification

Serverless and Microservices for AWS -

Oct 2020

LinkedIn

http://www.linkedin.com/learning/serverless-and-microservicesfor-aws?trk=flagship-

lil_details_certification&trk=lil_details_certification

Learning Amazon Web Services Lambda

Oct 2020

- LinkedIn

http://www.linkedin.com/learning/learning-amazon-webservices-lambda-2?trk=flagshiplil_details_certification&trk=lil_details_certification

How to Install a Free SSL Certificate using Let's Encrypt - Udemy Oct 2020

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-92c5b377-ccbe-4d5a-9b11-9387a48d7ba3/

Learn to Host Multiple Domains on one

Oct 2020

Virtual Server - Udemy

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-4c6e7d8f-01d1-43f7-89f2-94e4851917e1/

How the Internet Works & the Web

Oct 2020

Development Process - Udemy

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-1fe8f249-92d2-4a2f-a5ac-f61760b74cff/

Projects

Panchakarma

Research Project(Machine learning usage)
My contribution is feedback validation

Technologies - Spring BootFramework, ReactJs, MySQL, Flask

Kerberos Authentication POC Project

Kerberos, Spring Boot

React Chat App

React Hooks and Socket.io

Respotory - https://github.com/dilanSuraj/react-chat-app

CI/CD

Languages

English

Sinhala

Qualities

- More Passion towards back-end development
- Interested in engaging in analytical based activities
- Self motivated
- Ability to work in team environment as well as independently.

Procument Construction Application

Web Based Application

Repository -

https://github.com/dilanSuraj/Procument_Construction_Industry_Repo

Technologies - Spring Boot Framework, AngularJS, PhpMyAdmin, Ionic

Code Complexity Tool

Web Based Application

Repository - https://github.com/gtechninjas/spm-complexity-tool/tree/dilan

Technologies - Spring Boot Framework, Angular JS, PhpMyAdmin

Inventory and Distribution Management System

Web Based Application

Technologies - Spring MVC Framework, Bootstrap, PhpMyAdmin, HQL

Online Help Desk

Web Based Application

Technologies - Java, Bootstrap, MySql

BOC Mobile App

Re-design the App

Repository - https://github.com/gtechninjas/UEE-BOC-APP-FINAL/tree/dilan

Technologes - React Native, Spring Boot Framework

E-Train Book

Web Based Application

Repository -

https://github.com/dilanSuraj/IT17121002_DS_Assignment2

Technologies - React JS, Node/Express

Cab Reservation System

Web Based Application

Technologies - HTML,CSS, Javascript, MySql

E-commerce web application for a T-Shirt Company

Firebase/Firestore Serverless, React Js, Node Js

E-commerce web application for a

Phone case shop

Firebase/Firestore Serverless, React Js, Node Js

Food Based E-commerce web application

PostgresSQL, Node Js, DigitalOcean

FB Authentication using Passport JS

github.com/dilanSuraj/FB_Authentication

Chatbot

Python, Tensorflow

Repository - https://github.com/dilanSuraj/chatbot

Spring Security Project

github.com/dilanSuraj/SpringSecurityProject

Musician App

Node JS, React JS, AWS

Repository - https://github.com/dilanSuraj/musician-app

Image Classification Model

Python

Repository - https://github.com/dilanSuraj/PythonClassification

Automated web scrapper

stupefied-mclean-1bc8c3.netlify.app

Simple AR Application

github.com/dilanSuraj/simple-ar-app

Medical appointment no-show appointment predictor model

Python

Repository - https://github.com/dilanSuraj/No-show-appointment-predictor

React google map

React Js, Google Map API

Repository - https://github.com/dilanSuraj/simple-react-google-map-app

References

Don Rajitha Dissanayake - Tech Lead

Zone24x7 (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo

+94710735974, rajithadon@gmail.com

Voshitha Hettiarachchi - Program Manager

IFS Research & Development (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo

+94772326022, voshitha.hettiarachchi@ifsworld.com